Recall our shortcut for building the Laplacian.
Start by throwing out the directions on all the directed edges.
The diagonals of the Laplacian are just the degrees of each vertex.
So for instance vertex zero has one, two, three,
four, five, six, seven incident edges.
Therefore there's a seven in the zero, zero position.
Now the off diagonals mark at the edges.
For instance vertex zero is connected to every vertex except seven.
So it has a minus one in all the positions of row zero, except for
column seven.
As a sanity check on the answer, you can do some simple tests.
For instance, the matrix ought to be symmetric, look symmetric.
Symmetry follows from the definition of the Laplacian
in terms of the incidence matrix.
Symmetry.
Here's another sanity check, the rows and the columns should each sum to zero.
So does that hold for this solution?